Irfan Khan

Senior Full Stack Developer

• 0426604786 @ khanzz_irfan@hotmail.com ♂ github.com/khanzzirfan ♥ Sydney, Australia

SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer with over 10 years of experience in software development, consultant, Reactjs, NodeJS, C#, AWS, Azure. Led development of \$1M research project which was deemed a "gold standard" by the client. Increased client's revenue 2-fold after finetuning various techniques for Open Loyalty program in ReactJs. Wellaquainted with usability testing, a11y accessibility, integrations, continous development & deployments and automated testing.

EXPERIENCE

Team Lead / Senior Full stack Developer

IAG Insurance 06/2021 - Present Sydney, Australia Designed and developed intuitive and user-friendly interfaces for multiple web applications resulting in a 30% increase in user satisfaction

- Architected and developed large scale ReactJS application for lovalty project.
- · Developed webpack MFEs in ReactJS applications
- Developed classname pre processor for React components using tailwindcss.
- · Developed design system components using Storybook and React.
- Collaborated with designers and back-end developers to ensure seamless integration of UI components.
- Design and development of microservices with combination of Nestjs and Kafka message brokers.
- Implemented bff (backend for frontend) API layer to interact with microservices easily
- Implemented open loyalty product and integrated with insurance customers to give away loyalty points.
- · Added REST client code generation from OpenAPI specs
- Implemented automated testing in Codeceptis and deployment processes, reducing production errors by 25%.

Full Stack Developer / UI Coach

Westpac Bank 11/2018 - 06/2021 Sydney URL

Westpac is Australia's oldest bank and company, one of four major banking organisations in Australia and one of the largest banks in New Zealand.

- UI Coach and responsible for training project teams front-end developers
- · Developed a Westpac Gel design system library for banking group.
- Developed user interface by using the React JS, Redux for SPA development.
- Involved in responsive design and developed a single ISOMORPHIC responsive website that could be served to desktop, Tablets and mobile users using React JS.
- Component for UX-Library consisted of Button, Checkbox, Input, Icons, Toggle Button, Dropdown, Multi-Level Dropdown and many more.
- · Developed centralized MFA system for all Westpac applications.
- Achieved role-based access to the application and used SSO for the integrated product and plugins.
- Developed enterprise testing framework using codeceptjs and selenium webdriver io. Trained application developers on codeceptjs framework and CI/CD integration.
- References
- https://one.dev1.ui.westpac.com.au/react/gel/docs/latest

Client-Side

HTML • CSS • JS • React • React native •

Redux • TypeScript • Styled components •

React-router • React-query • GraphQL • ES6 •

Nextjs

Server-side

C# . NodeJS . NestJS . Aws Lambda . Nextjs .

Postgresql • Redis • Kafka • ExpressJS •

MySQL · AWS · MongoDB · HTTP/2

Development & Operations

Jest - Playwright - CodeceptJs - Mocha -

Scrum · Agile · GIT · Git workflows ·

Bamboo · AWS

PROJECTS

Eyecast Video Editor

Australia

React based canvas editor for videos, images, etc.

- Designed and Architected video editing software from start
- · Implemented React-Pixi, Pixijs, threejs for canvas elements
- · Implemented performant timeline scrubber using Konvajs.
- Embedded Remotion Player for Video editing in ReactJS
- Exported video using Remotion and Lambdas
- Used redux-sagas to retrieve backend data asynchronously
- Designed and implemented serverless NodeJS restful apis for backend
- Developed user interface by using the React JS, Redux for SPA development.
- Raised \$500,000 funding from investors.
- What was a successful outcome of your work? (e.g. Raised \$3,000 for the charity)
- · References:

https://dv855xav0od7t.cloudfront.net/canva

https://d3704nhg03uhyb.cloudfront.net/dashboard

STRENGTHS

Team Leadership Introduction to Leadership course by **IAG** Insurance

EXPERIENCE

Senior Full Stack Developer

ANZ Bank 11/2016 - 10/2018 New Zealand.

Company Description

- · A major role in developing React & Redux app to delivery high
- Involved in application design and demonstrating the architectural implementation through code and proof of concept for banking workflows
- Implemented node.js RESTful api's and a middleware system to call backend restful apis
- Unit test for node.js api's, react components, action creators, reducers, containers
- Developing working knowledge of all software development and internal Microsoft architectural standards and design patterns
- Collaborate with designers to create clean interfaces and simple, intuitive interaction and experience.
- Code review, Walk through and deployment across different environments.
- Working along with test lead, implemented parallel tests, page object factories in selenium with Nunit framework.
- . Awarde

Best user experience award at ANZ 2017.

Software Developer

LIC, Hamilton 02/2016 - 10/2016 New Zealand

LIC is an agritech and herd improvement co-operative which empowers livestock farmers through the delivery of superior genetics and technology.

- Ongoing web development using ReactJS, Redux, C# MVC, Web API, client portion of the application use Reactjs, other node modules and backend is on SQL database.
- Complete detailed programming and development tasks for front end public and internal website as well as challenging backend server code.
- Collaborate with designers to create clean interfaces and simple, intuitive interaction and experience.
- · Created dynamic ReactJS reporting framework and printing.
- Optimizing web assets for optimal speed and performance.
- Make suggestions for improving the product in every elaboration meetings.
- Participating in discussions with clients and business to clarify the requirements

Software Developer

Endev NZ 03/2015 - 01/2016 New Zealand Company Description

- Ongoing web development using C# MVC, Web API and EF, client portion of the application use JavaScript, JQuery and leverage the bootstrap front end framework and backend portion is completely based on SQL database.
- Involved in database design, writing and optimizing complex stored procedures.
- Coordinated and led execution of a migration from SQL 2008 to SQL 2012.
- Involved in performance tuning in .Net and T-SQL and Reporting services.
- Involved in designing modules such as booking engine, score card processes, audit tracking, NZ post API etc
- Performing consistent coding and documentation to the company standards.
- · Created and executed TestComplete automated Test Scripts.
- · Participated in Bug Triage meetings.

STRENGTHS

Communication

Attended a Communication course at **Agility Training**.

AWARDS

Best UI Design

Awarded for designing and developing an innovative user interface that improved user engagement by 30%.

AWS Certified Cloud Practioner

ACHIEVEMENTS

Developing MFEs and Json Schema React Components

Led the frontend development team in building a robust JSON schema forms for ReactJs Apps. Banks has deployed 20 forms in a month time during Covid, improved code reusability, rapid deployments and business satisfaction.

Mentoring Junior Developers

Provided guidance and mentorship to junior developers, resulting in their successful completion of several high-profile projects and increased team productivity.

Outstanding Performance

Recognized for consistently exceeding project expectations and delivering quality code on time and within budget.

FIND ME ONLINE

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/irfan-khan-2a847455/

GitHub

https://github.com/khanzzirfan

EXPERIENCE

Junior Software Developer

Agility CIS Ltd 06/2011 - 02/2015 New Zealand The Orion, the complete solution for electricity, gas, telecommunications and water utilities

- · Responsible for full lifecycle development.
- · Involved in requirement gathering and design document.
- Client meetings to discuss project progress, deadlines and on site trainings
- Designed database maintenance plans to set up core maintenance tasks.
- Rebuilding/Monitoring the indexes at regular intervals for better performance.
- Involved in troubleshooting and fine-tuning of database for its performance
- · Recovering the databases from backup in disasters
- Tuning queries which are running slow using SQL Profiler and Statistics IO by different methods in terms of evaluating joins, indexes, updating statistics and code modification
- Document the code consistently throughout the development process.
- Created various reports according to the business requirements and deployed to SQL reporting services.
- Create processes and complex stored procedures and T-SQL queries for application code and database object migration to support efficient and reliable system development lifecycle.

EDUCATION

B.Sc. in Computer Science

Osmania Unversity

2007 - 2010 Hyderabad, India GPA 6 / 6